[Music]
Wonder by RJ palaso the deal MOM AND MR. TUSHMAN were talking
when we got back to the office. Mrs.
Garcia was the first to see us come back, and she started smiling her shiny smile
as we walked in. “So, August, what did you think? Did you like what you saw?” she
asked. “Yeah.” I nodded, looking over at Mom.
Jack, Julian, and Charlotte were standing by the door, not sure where to go or if
they were still needed. I wondered what else they've been told about me before
they’d met me. “Did you see the baby chick?”
Mom asked me. As I shook my head, Julian said: “Are you talking about the baby
chicks in science? Those get donated to a farm at the end of every school year.” “Oh,”
said Mom, disappointed. “But they hatch new ones every year in science,” Julian added. “So
August will be able to see them again in the spring.” “Oh, good,” said Mom, eyeing me.
“They were so cute, August.” I wish you
wouldn’t talk to me like I was a baby in
front of other people. “So, August,” said Mr.
Tushman, “did these guys show you around enough or do you want to see more? I
realize I forgot to ask them to show you the gym.” “We did anyway, Mr. Tushman,” said Julian.
“Excellent!” said Mr. Tushman. “And I told him about the school play and some of the
electives,” said Charlotte. “Oh no!” she said suddenly. “We forgot to show him the art
room!” “That’s okay,” said Mr. Tushman. “But we can show it to him now,” Charlotte offered.
“Don’t we have to pick Via up soon?” I said
to Mom. That was our signal for my telling Mom if I really wanted to
leave. “Oh, you’re right,” said Mom, getting up.
I could tell she was pretending to check the time on her watch. “I’m sorry,
everybody. I lost track of the time. We have to go pick up my daughter at her
new school. She’s taking an unofficial tour today.” This part wasn’t a lie: that
Via was checking out her new school today. The part that was a lie was that
we were picking her up at the school, which we weren’t. She was coming home
with Dad later. “Where does she go to school?” asked Mr. Tushman, getting
up she She’s starting fuler High School this fall.” “Wow, that’s not an easy school
to get into. Good for her!” “Thank you,” said
Mom, nodding. “It’ll be a bit of a schlep,
though. The A train down to 86 then the cross town bus all the way to the East
Side. Takes an hour that way but it’s just a 15minute drive.” “It’ll be worth it.
I know a couple of kids who got into fauler and love it,” said Mr. Tushman. “We
really should go, Mom,” I said, tugging at her pocketbook. We said goodbye kind of
quickly after that. I think Mr. Tushman was a little surprised that we were
leaving so suddenly, and then I wondered if he would blame Jack and Charlotte,
even though it was really only Julian who made me feel kind of bad. “Everyone
was really nice,” I made sure to tell Mr.
Tushman before we left. “I look forward to having you as a student,” said Mr. Tushman,
patting my back. “Bye,” I said to Jack, Charlotte, and Julian, but I didn’t look
at them— —or look up at all— —until I left the
building home AS SOON AS we had walked at least half a block from the school,
Mom said: “So how’d it go? Did you like it?”
“Not yet, Mom. When we get home,” I said. The
moment we got inside the house, I ran to my room and threw myself onto my bed. I
could tell Mom didn’t know what was up, and I guess I really didn’t, either. I
felt very sad and a tiny bit happy at the exact same time, kind of like that
laughing crying feeling all over again.
My dog, Daisy, followed me into the room, jumped on the bed, and started licking me
all over my face. “Who’s a good girly I
said in my Dad voice. “Who’s a good girly Is everything okay, sweetness?” Mom
said. She wanted to sit down beside me but Daisy was hogging the bed. “Excuse me,
Daisy.” She sat down, nudging Daisy over.
“Were those kids not nice to you, Auggie?” “Oh no,” I said, only half lying. “They were
okay.” “But were they nice? Mr. Tushman went out of his way to tell me what sweet
kids they are.” “Uh-huh.” I nodded, but I kept looking at Daisy, kissing her on the nose
nose and rubbing her ear until her back leg did that little flea scratch
shake. “That boy Julian seemed especially nice,” Mom said. “Oh, no, he was the least
nice. I like Jack, though. He was nice. I thought his name was Jack Will but it’s
just Jack.” “Wait, maybe I’m getting them confused. Which one was the one with the
dark hair that was brushed forward?” “Julian.” “And he wasn’t nice?” “No, not
nice.” “Oh.” She thought about this for a second. “Okay, so is he the kind of kid
who’s one way in front of grown-ups and another way in front of
kids?” “Yeah, I guess.” “Ah, hate those,” she answered, nodding. “He was like, ‘So, August,
what’s the deal with your face?’” I said, looking at Daisy the whole time. “‘Were you
in a fire or something thing Mom didn’t say anything. When I
looked up at her, I could tell she was completely
shocked. “He didn’t say it in a mean way,” I said quickly. “He was just asking.” Mom
nodded. “But I really like Jack,” I said. “He was like, ‘Shut up, Julian!’ And Charlotte
was like, ‘You’re so rude, Julian!’” Mom nodded again. She pressed her fingers on
her forehead like she was was pushing against a headache. “I’m so sorry, Auggie,” she said
quietly. Her cheeks were bright red. “No, it’s okay, Mom, really.” “You don’t have to
go to school if you don’t want, sweetie.” “I want to,” I said.
“Auggie “Really, Mom. I want to.” And I wasn’t lying First Day
Jitters OKAY, SO I admit that the first day of school I was so nervous that the
butterflies in my stomach were more like pigeons flying around my
insides. Mom and Dad were probably a little nervous, too, but they acted all
excited for me, taking pictures of me and Via before we left the house since it
was Via’s first day of school, too. Up until a few days before, we still weren’t
sure I would be going to school at all.
After my tour of the school, Mom and Dad had reverse sides on whether I should go
or not. Mom was now the one saying I shouldn’t go and Dad was saying I should.
Dad had told me he was really proud of how I’d handled myself with Julian and
that I was turning into quite the strong man. And I heard him tell Mom that he now
thought she had been right all along. But Mom, I could tell, wasn’t so sure anymore.
When Dad told her that he and Via wanted to walk me to school today, too, since it
was on the way to the subway station, Mom seemed relieved that we would all be
going together. And I guess I was, too. Even though beer Prep is just a few
blocks from our house, I’ve only been on that block a couple of times before. In
general, I try to avoid blocks where there are lots of kids roaming around. On
our block, everybody knows me and I know everybody. I know every brick and every
tree trunk and every crack in the sidewalk. I know Mrs. Grimaldi, the lady
who’s always sitting by her window, and the old guy who walks up and down the
street whistling like a bird. I know the deli on the corner where Mom gets our
bagels, and the waitresses at the coffee shop who all call me “honey” and give me
lollipops whenever they see me. I love my neighborhood of North River Heights,
which is why it was so strange to be walking down these blocks feeling like
it was all new to me suddenly asford Avenue, a street I’ve been down a million
times, looked totally different for some reason. Full of people I never saw before,
waiting for buses, pushing strollers. We crossed as Fort and turned
up Height's Place Thea walked next to me like she usually does, and Mom and Dad
were behind us. As soon as we turned the corner, we saw all the kids in front of
the school— —hundreds of them talking to each other in little groups, laughing, or
standing with their parents, who were talking with other parents. I kept my head way
down. “Everyone’s just as nervous as you are,” said Via in my ear. “Just remember
that this is everyone’s first day of school. Okay?” Mr. Tushman was greeting
students and parents in front of the school entrance. I have to admit: so far,
nothing bad had happened. I didn’t catch anyone staring or even noticing me. Only
once did I look up to see some girls looking my way and whispering with their
hands cuffed over their mouths, but they looked away when they saw me notice them.
We reached the front entrance. “Okay, so this is it, big boy,” said
Dad, putting his hands on top of my shoulders. “Have a great first day. I love
you,” said Via, giving me a big kiss and a hug. “You, too,” I said.
“I love you Augie said Dad, hugging me.
“Bye.” Then Mom hugged me, but I could tell she was about to cry, which would have
totally embarrassed me, so I just gave her a fast hard hug, turned, and disappeared into the
school locks I WENT STRAIGHT to room 301 on the third floor. Now I was glad I’d
gone on that little tour, because I knew exactly where to go and didn’t have to
look up once. I noticed that some kids were definitely staring at me now. I did
my thing of pretending not to notice. I went inside the classroom, and
the teacher was writing on the chalkboard while all the kids started
sitting at different desks. The desks were in half circle facing the
chalkboard, so I chose the desk in the middle toward the back, which I thought
would make it harder for anyone to stare at me. I still kept my head way down, just
looking up enough from under my bangs to see everyone’s feet. As the desks started
to fill up, I did notice that no one sat down next to me. A couple of times
someone was about to sit next to me and changed his or her mind at the last
minute and sat somewhere else. “Hey, August.” It was Charlotte, giving
me her little wave as she sat down at a desk in the front of the class. Why
anyone would ever choose to sit way up front in a class, I don’t know.
“Hey,” I said, nodding hello. Then I noticed Julian was sitting a few seats away from
her, talking to some other kids. I know he saw me, but he didn’t say hello. Suddenly
someone was sitting down next to me. It was Jack Will. Jack. “What’s up,” he said,
nodding at me. “Hey, Jack,” I answered, waving my hand, which I immediately wished I
hadn’t done because it felt kind of UN cool Okay, kids, okay, everybody! Settle
down,” said the teacher, now facing us. She had written her name Miss poosa on the
chalkboard. “Everybody find a seat, please.
Come in,” she said to a couple of kids who
had just walked in the room. “There’s a seat there, and right there.” She hadn’t
noticed me yet. “Now, the first thing I want everyone to do is stop talking and
She noticed me.
put your backpacks down and quiet down.” She had only hesitated for a millionth
of a second, but I could tell the moment
she saw me. Like I said: I’m used to it by
now. “I’m going to take attendance and do the seating chart,” she continued, sitting
on the edge of her desk. Next to her were three neat rows of accordion
folders. “When I call your name, come up and I’ll hand you a folder with your
name on it. It contains your class schedule schule and your combination
lock, which you should not try to open until I tell you to. Your locker number
is written on the class schedule. Be forewarned that some lockers are not
right outside this class but down the hall, and before anyone even thinks of
asking: no, you cannot switch lockers and you can’t switch locks. Then if there’s
time at the end of this period, we’re all
going to get to know each other a little better, okay? Okay picked up the clipboard
on her desk and started reading the names out loud. “Okay, so, Julian Ain she
said, looking up. Julian raised his hand and said “Here” at the same time. “Hi, Julian,”
she said, making a note on her seating chart. She picked up the very first
folder and held it out toward him. “Come pick it up,” she said, kind of No Nonsense
He got up and took it from her zamina Chin?” She handed a folder to each kid as
she read off the names. As she went down the list, I noticed that the seat next to
me was the only one still empty, even though there were two kids sitting at
one desk just a few seats away. When she
called the name of one of them, a big kid named Henry Joplin who already looked
like a teenager, she said: “Henry, there’s an empty desk right over there. Why don’t
you take that seat, okay?” She handed him his folder and pointed to the desk next
to mine. Although I didn’t look at him directly, I could tell Henry did not want
to move next to me, just by the way he dragged his backpack on the floor as he
came over, like he was moving in slow motion. Then he plopped his backpack up
really high on the right side of the desk so it was kind of like a wall
between his desk and mine. “Maya marwitz Miss poza was saying. “Here,” said a girl
about four dusts down from me. “Miles Nory Here,” said the kid that had been sitting
with Henry Joplin. As he walked back to his desk, I saw him shoot Henry a “poor
you” look. “August Pullman?” said Miss poosa Here,” I said quietly, raising my hand a
bit. “Hi, August,” she said, smiling at me very nicely when I went up to get my
folder. I kind of felt everyone’s eyes burning into my back for the few seconds
I stood in the front of the class, and everybody looked down when I walked back
to my desk. I resisted spinning the combination when I sat down, even though
everyone else was doing it, because she had specifically told us not to. I was
already pretty good at opening locks, anyway, because I’ve used them on my bike.
Henry kept trying to open his lock but couldn’t do it. He was getting frustrated
and kind of cursing under his breath Miss ptoa called out the next few names.
The last name was Jack Will. After she she handed Jack his
folder, she said: “Okay, so, everybody write your combinations down somewhere safe
that you won’t forget, okay? But if you do forget, which happens at least 3.2 times
per semester, Mrs. Garcia has a list of all the combination numbers. Now go ahead,
take your locks out of your folders and spend a couple of minutes practicing how
to open them, though I know some of you went ahead and did that anyway.” She was
looking at Henry when she said that. “And in the meanwhile, I’ll tell you guys a
little something about myself. And then you guys can tell me a little about
yourselves and we’ll, um, get to know each other. Sound good? Good.” She smiled at
everyone that I felt like she was smiling at me the most. It wasn’t a shiny
smile, like Mrs. Garcia’s smile, but a normal smile, like she meant it. She
looked very different from what I thought teachers were going to look like.
I guess I thought she’d look like Miss foul from Jimmy Neutron an old lady with
a big bun on top of her head. But, in fact, she looked exactly like M Mothma from
Star Wars Episode 4 haircut kind of like a boy and a big white shirt kind of like
a tunic. She turned around and started writing on the chalkboard. Henry still couldn’t get his
lock to open, and he was getting more and more frustrated every time someone else
popped one open. He got really annoyed when I was able to open mine on the
first try. The funny thing is, if he hadn’t put the backpack between us, I
most definitely would have offered to help him around the room Miss pza TOLD US a
little about who she was. It was boring stuff about where she originally came
from, and how she always wanted to teach, and she left her job on Wall Street
about six years ago to pursue her “dream” and teach kids. She ended by asking if
anyone had any questions, and Julian raised his hand. “Yes She had to look at
the list to remember his name. “Julian.” “That’s cool about how you pursued your
dream,” he said. “Thank you!” “You’re welcome!” He smiled
proudly. “Okay, so why don’t you tell us a little about yourself, Julian? Actually,
here’s what I want everyone to do. Think of two things you want other people to
know about you. Actually, wait a minute: how many of you came from the Beacher
lower school? About half the kids raised their hands. “Okay, so a few of you already
know each other. But the rest of you, I guess, are new to the school, right? Okay,
so everyone think of two things you want the other people to know about you— —and
if you know some of the other kids, try to think of things they don’t already
know about you Okay. So let’s start with Julian and we’ll go around the room.”
Julian scrunched up his face and started tapping his forehead like he was
thinking really hard. “Okay, whenever you’re ready Miss poosa said. “Okay, so
number one is that—” “Do me a favor and start with your names, okay Miss Bosa
interrupted. “It’ll help me remember everyone.” “Oh, okay. So my name is Julian.
And the number one thing I’d like to tell everyone about my self is that I
just got Battleground Mystic for my Wii and it’s totally awesome. And the number
two thing is that we got a ping pong table this summer.” “Very nice, I love
pingpong said Miss pza Does anyone have any questions for Julian?” “Is Battleground
Mystic multiplayer or one player?” said the kid named
Miles. “Not those kinds of questions, guys,” said Miss Bosa Okay, so how about you. She pointed
to Charlotte, probably because her desk was closest to the
front. “Oh, sure.” Charlotte didn’t hesitate for even a second, like she knew exactly
what she wanted to say. “My name is Charlotte. I have two sisters, and we just
got a new puppy named Suki in July. We got her from an animal shelter and she’s
so, so cute!” “That’s great, Charlotte, thank you,” said Miss pza Okay, then, who’s next
[Music]